# Alanoud Alrajaan

# ABOUT ME

An Engineer with Information security experience and an academic background in Networking and Telecommunication Systems. I have had the opportunity to exercise aspects of my academic gained knowledge in my career but I am looking forward to new challenges that would enable me to grow furthermore. I am a fast- learner, goal-oriented, motivated and dependable person.

# EDUCATION

2014 - 2019 • princess Noura University Bachelor of science in Computer Science Networking and Telecommunication Systems.

#### LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native. English: Advanced.

# EXPERIENCE

2021-present

Omer k.Alesayi & Co. LTD (MVPI)

**Network Engineer** 

#### 2020-2021

#### Makman Solutions (LLC).

#### **Information Security Specialist**

- Identity protection for personal and enterprise privacy protection.
- Identify and remove more than 2000 illegal content on web.
- $\bullet$  Maintains high quality SLA to ensure consumers satisfaction.
- Analysing, Planning, Monitoring and Reporting such as:KPI.

#### 2019-2020

#### Bussma Valuation

#### **Network Specialist**

- $\bullet$  Office 365 administrator and Email management.
- Building valuation reports for the ERP system.
- · Building the female section from scratch, providing the devices and the needed connectivity.
- Arrange Backup solution.

# 2019

#### Data Center - PNU

#### **Trainee**

- · Scan the network for security gaps.
- Find the Vulnerability and seek the solutions to solve it.
- Secure email gateway & email advance threat prevention Endpoint
- Reviewing ISO27001 policies.
- procedures Drafting cybersecurity awareness messages & content.

### SKILLS

Negotiating & persuading.

Creativity and flexibility.

Team-working.

Leadership and organization.

# Projects

- · Analyze internet users accounts for legal issues.
- · HR solution SAAS.
- Asset management, professional inventory with labeling and assigning devices to the users.
- · Graduation project (A novel bi-model biometric system based fusion of heart and speech information).

# Courses

- ITILv4 Digital and IT Strategy.
- Cloud Essentials.
- Participated at Cyber Saber Hackathon 2018.
- (Proofpoint Technical Training) course Protection Server: Basics -Level1.
  (CompTIA Security +) certificate (Course for 11 hours.)
  (CompTIA NETWORK+) certificate (Course for 32 hours.)

- (MATLAB) certificate. (Course for 9.5 hours.)

# References

References available upon request.